downlopedia.com 2013-01-22

# Downlopedia | Privacy Policy

### Privacy Policy

**“Downlopedia pledges to you that it will never spam you, or harm your online privacy in any way.  
Downlopedia takes your online privacy seriously and is committed to providing you with a safe and secure working environment.  
Even so, with the increasing amount of spam and spywares flooding the Internet it’s difficult not to be skeptical. The following are the most common questions you are likely to ask yourself:  
Is Downlopedia promoting spyware or malware?  
No, it does not. Downlopedia does not install any PC surveillance tools, capture keystrokes, log your communications, etc. Our business and revenue model has nothing to do with using your personal information in a harmful or deceitful manner. In fact, the Downlopedia team is adamantly against that kind of behavior and therefore, does not violate the privacy policy and agreement with our customers.  
Downlopedia is 100% Safe & Secure  
Detailed Privacy Policy:  
 At Downlopedia, we respect the privacy of our users and the importance of the information they entrust to us. We summarize below the basic information policies and practices in place at the Downlopedia.com website.  
 The Downlopedia.com Privacy Policy was last updated on: December 1, 2011.  
Personal Information we may collect                                                                
We may collect information that can identify you (“personal information”), such as your name and email address, (i) when you (or other users) provide it to us when using our website or in some other manner, or (ii) from other Downlopedia businesses, from our business partners, and from other third parties.  We may combine the personal information that we receive from different sources.  
We also may collect other types of information in the following ways when you visit our website:  
Our server logs automatically collect information, such as your IP address, your browser type and language, and the date and time of your visit, which helps us track users’ movements around our site and understand trends.  
We may assign your computer one or more cookies which may collect information to facilitate access to our website and to personalize your online experience.  
We may use standard Internet tools, such as web beacons which collect information that tracks your use of our website and enables us to customize our services and advertisements.  
We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. Should we ever do so, we will comply with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act.  
Information others may collect  
We may allow third-party advertising companies or ad networks to display advertisements or place ad tags on our websites.  
We do not provide any personal information to these companies. These companies may use tracking tools, such as cookies, to collect information about computers used to view or interact with their advertisements. Some of these companies may be members of the [Network Advertising Initiative](http://www.networkadvertising.org/%22%20%5Ct%20%22_blank), which offers consumers the ability to opt out of ad targeting by all member companies.  
If you post information about yourself or others, or communicate with others using our website, please note that we cannot control who reads your postings or what they do with the information you provide. We encourage you to use caution in posting personal information.  
How we may use information we collect  
We may use information to:  
·         Fulfill your requests for products and services;  
·         Offer products and services that may be of interest to you;  
·         Customize the advertising and/or content that you see on our websites;  
·         Facilitate use of our websites;  
·         Manage your account and your preferences;  
·         Analyze use of and improve our websites, products and services;  
·         Identify and protect against fraudulent transactions and other misuses of our websites; and  
·         Enforce any EULA, terms of use, terms of service or other terms/policies governing your use of the Downlopedia.com website.  
Security   
We take appropriate physical, electronic, and other security measures to help safeguard personal information from unauthorized access, alteration, or disclosure.  
Opt-Out:  
At any time, you may opt-out of receiving any email, newsletters or other communication by contacting us at support@download-nation.com. At any time you can email us and detail what exactly do you want to opt out from. We commit to opt you out of any service within 72 hours of your email.  
Changes to our Privacy Policy  
We may occasionally update our Privacy Policy to reflect changes in our practices and services. If we make material changes in the way we collect, use, or share your personal information, we will notify you by sending you an email to the email address you most recently provided to us and/or by prominently posting notice of the changes on our website.  
How to contact us  
If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy please contact us by email: [support@downlopedia.com](mailto:general-inqueries@downlopedia.com).  
© 2011 Downlopedia. All rights reserved.

 GLOSSARY:  
Cookies:  
A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user’s computer for record keeping purposes. Cookies can be either session cookies or persistent cookies. A session cookie expires when you close your browser and is used to make it easier for you to navigate our website. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time.  
Through the use of a cookie, we also may automatically collect information about your online activity on our site, such as the web pages you visit, the links you click, and the searches you conduct on our site. If accounts are offered, when you sign into your account, we may record your user or member ID and the name on your user or member account in the cookie file on your computer. We also may record your password in this cookie file, if you indicated that you would like your password saved for automatic sign-in. For security purposes, we will encrypt any usernames, passwords, and other user or member account-related data that we store in such cookies. In the case of sites and services that do not use a user or member ID, the cookie will contain a unique identifier. We may allow our authorized service providers to serve cookies from our website to allow them to assist us in various activities, such as doing analysis and research on the effectiveness of our site, content and advertising.  
You may delete or decline cookies by changing your browser settings. (Click “Help” in the toolbar of most browsers for instructions.) If you do so, some of the features and services of our website may not function properly.  
Web Beacons:  
Web beacons (also known as clear gifs, pixel tags or web bugs) are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of web users or to access cookies. Unlike cookies which are stored on the user’s computer hard drive, web beacons are embedded invisibly on the web pages (or in email) and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence.  
Web beacons may be used to deliver or communicate with cookies, to count users who have visited certain pages and to understand usage patterns. We also may include web beacons in promotional [or other] e-mail messages or newsletters to determine whether messages have been opened and acted upon. We also may receive an anonymous identification number if you come to our site from an online advertisement displayed on a third-party website

**
